MICHAEL BRUCATO

Chicago, IL 60641 • 847-650-2045 • <u>brucatomike1@gmail.com</u> • <u>LinkedIn.com/michael-brucato</u>

ADMINISTRATIVE ASSISTANT

An organized, detail-oriented, and thorough administrative assistant possessing a strong work ethic. A forward-thinking creative with strong analytical and research acumen combined with a collaborative, loyal, and dedicated nature. Committed to championing quality over quality, implements cost-saving and time-saving solutions to complex problems. Valued for assuming leadership and initiative to lead in a fast-paced environment working towards a common goal.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

Day-to-Day Operations • Project Management • Research • Data Entry • Bookkeeping • Scheduling • Report Writing • Relationship Cultivation • Budgeting • Training & Development • Management • Data Analysis • Operations • Presentations • Communications • Inventory Control

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

CAREERBUILDER EMPLOYMENT SCREENING, Rolling Meadows, IL

2012 to 2020

Records Analyst • 2014 TO 2020

Delivered timely and accurate investigation into criminal histories of job applicants for a \$50M firm specializing in background, employment, and drug investigations.

- Streamlined Processes & Procedures: Reduced turnaround time from 30 days to 24/48 hours (~95%) for statewide record search by facilitating online registration for the State of Kentucky with the State's Court while incurring no additional costs. Maintained compliance and safety standards and implemented a new system within days.
- **Detail Oriented Research:** Developed and deployed more comprehensive research procedures while adhering to FCRA guidelines; doubled the accuracy (hit rate) and identification of federal criminal searches.
- **Team Leadership:** Hand-selected to supervise a team of six, served as a resource for new employees, and promoted a positive and productive office culture.
- Subject Matter Expertise: Served as subject matter expert and lead front-end and backend design contributor on a \$2M automation project for a large national criminal database; reduced data points from 1000s to a few hundred saving time and money.
- Training & Development: Documented new training procedures based on improved processes and systems for database searches, company reporting policy, and research procedures. Facilitated training to global operations team via Zoom, yielding a reduced error rate for all employees.

Fingerprinting Technician • 2012 TO 2014

Began role as fingerprinting technician at Aurico Reports before being aquired by CareeerBuilder in 2016. Charged with overseeing the department in processing fingerprints as requested by public and private institutions.

- Exceeded Goals: Exceeded department goal of maintaining an error rate at less than 1% (goal was 2%) by focusing on quality over quantity while delivering on-time and on-budget.
- Business Development: Grew client base from an average of 50 per day to 65 per day. A 30% increase by providing exceptional client service.

EDUCATION & LICENSURE

M. Brucato | 847-650-2045 | <u>brucatomike1@gmail.com</u>

Resume Page 2

COURSEWORK IN MUSIC OF BACHELOR OF ARTS IN MUSIC)

College of Lake County, Grayslake, IL Illinois Institute of Art, Schaumburg, IL

TRANSPORTATION WORKERS IDENTIFICATION CREDENTIAL (TWIC)

Department of Homeland Security, Issued August 2013

PERMANENT EMPLOYEE REGISTRATION CARD (PERC)

Illinois Department of Financial & Professional Regulation, Issued May 2012